When we were talking about histogram modification, either equalization or
当谈到直方图修正 无论是直方图均衡化
matching, we were replacing the grey value of a pixel only based on its actual
还是直方图匹配 我们只依据像素的灰度值本身进行替换
grey value. And we weren't looking at the surrounding
而不会考虑该像素周围的图像区域
area of the image. What we're going to do next is we're
接下来我们要做的
going to do spatial operations. So, we're going to basically replace the
是空间操作 我们将
pixel value at the given pixel depending on what's happening around the pixel.
依据给定像素周围的情况 替换其像素值
So, there's going to be influence of the neighborhood.
所以 邻域就会产生影响
So if we have a complete image, we're going to look at the pixel and we see
假如我们有一幅完整的图像 考虑这个像素
here magnifications of that, or let us observe here.
这里是这一部分的放大图 或者观察这里
We're going to decide what to replace the pixel value here with depending on what's
我们会根据这个像素的周围像素 决定如何替换它的像素值
happening around it. So, it's not going to be any more just
那就不再是我行我素了
okay, I decide how am I going to change depending on my own pixel value. We're
不再是只根据像素值本身来决定如何变化
going to say how these pixel's going to change depending on neighborhood pixels.
像素的改变将依赖于邻域像素
And the simplest of those operations is basically averaging.
最简单的处理方式就是取平均值
So, we are going to replace the pixel here by the average of let's say, a three
所以我们可以将这个像素值 比如说 替换为
by three neighborhood around it. Of course, we have to normalize.
它附近 3x3 区域内像素值的平均值 当然 我们需要归一化
If we are averaging nine pixels, we have to divide by nine.
如果是对 9 个像素取平均 我们就要除以9
We can also do weighted averages, so we can average in a sense that, yourself,
我们还可以做加权平均 比如在某种情况下
the pixel its self, waits four.
像素本身的权重是4
And those that are in four neighborhood, remember we talked about four and eight
而 4邻域中的像素 我们讨论过 4邻域 和 8邻域结构
neighborhood structures, those are, are in four will count double and those that
4邻域中的像素 按权重为2 来计算
are in diagonal, we just count single. And then, we basically align sixteen
对角线上的像素 其权重为1 这样我们就分配好了16个权
things, 1 + 2 is 3, + 1 is 4, + 2 is 6, and so on.
1+2是3 再+1是4 再+2是6 以此类推
So, we will have to normalize by sixteen. So this is just an average, this is a
所以我们需要除以16进行归一化 这个是直接平均
weighted average. Let's see their facts of this in a real
而这个是加权平均 让我们看看真实图像中情况是怎样的
image. What we have here is an image, and this
这有一张图片
is a good image because it has structures of different sizes.
这是一个很好的示例图像 因为它上面有一系列不同大小的结构体
And what we are going to see for each one of these other images is that local
然后我们看一下其余这些经过局部平均处理的图像
average, and we take neighborhoods of different sizes.
每一个图像中我们选取不同大小的邻域
We go from three to thirteen. So this is 3, 5, 9, 15, and 35.
大小从 3x3 到 35x35 这是3、5、9、15 和35
So we go from three to 35. The, the larger the neighborhood, the
我们选取的区域从 3x3 到 35x35 邻域越大
more pixels we are averaging. And we see the effect of that.
平均处理的像素就越多 我们可以看到最终的效果
Here when we average by three we don't see much of a change, there is some
当平均的区域大小是 3x3 时 我们看不出什么变化
change here within the defined structure, but let's just jump to the 35.
虽然这些轮廓清晰的区域有一点变化 但先让我们来看看35
So this is a window of 35, a neighborhood of 35 and we see that a lot of things get
经过 35x35 大小的窗口 也就是 35x35 邻域处理后 我们看到很多东西变得模糊了
blurred and I'm going to explain in a second why, give you the intuition behind
我很快会解释这是为什么 直观上让你理解背后的原理
that. So a lot of the structure gets blurred.
可以看到 很多的结构都变得模糊了
If we are using a neighborhood of only 15, less things get blurred.
如果我们只用 15x15 的邻域处理 只会有较少的结构变得模糊
We see that here, for example, this is much easier to distinguish the bars here
比如 我们可以看到 这儿的竖条要比那儿的更容易辨认
than it is here. And, that depends on the distance between
那取决于物体间的距离
the objects. So, why are we getting blur?
为什么会变得模糊呢？
Because here, for example, this point. Imagine that we have a 35 by 35 window
因为 拿这一点当例子 想象它周围有一扇 35x35 的窗口
around it. So, we end up averaging the block of the
我们将该黑色像素点的周围的灰色区域取平均
pixel with the grey around it, and then it gets a bit brighter.
使得这一点变得更亮
So this was very dark, black. This is bright, and if we're averaging
这儿非常暗 是黑色 这比较亮
pixels around it, the average basically goes up for this pixel.
如果我们平均它周围的像素值 那么这个像素值会增大
And when we're averaging here, because some of the pixels in the neighbor, in
当我们在这做平均处理时 因为这周围的像素是黑色的
the neighborhood are dark, the average here would basically go down.
那么平均来说这里就会变暗
And then, we're clarifying this blurring effect.
接着我来解释模糊现象
Let me just illustrate with that one dimensional function.
让我用一个一维函数来说明
If I'm basically averaging this with this, and this, clearly the pixel value
如果我取这一点 这点 和这点进行平均 很明显
of this goes down because of the effect of this.
这一点的像素值会变小 因为这一点的影响
So, this will be replaced by something around here.
因此这一点的灰度值 会被这附近的灰度值代替
This one, if I'm averaging with this one and maybe
如果我将这一点 和这一点 还有这里的像素点取平均
with a pixel here, then it goes slightly up.
那么它的值会变大一些
And then, this perfectly sharp profile becomes a bit of a smooth profile because
于是这个极端陡峭的曲线 会变得比较平滑
I'm averaging things on the side. We're going to see later towards the
这正是因为我们做了平均 我们将在
second part of this course, how to basically average without rating these
课程的第二部分了解到 怎样在平均处理时避免模糊现象
blurring effect. But this is just to illustrate a very
但这只用来描述邻域平均中
simple operation which is local averaging,
一种非常简单的操作
and how neighbors, and basically the size of the neighbors affect what's happening
以及邻域的大小是怎样影响像素的
on the pixel. Now, you might wonder, is this operation
现在 你可能会问 这个操作重要么？
important? Yes, it is.
答案是相当重要
Although, it's going to blur. The basic idea is that we are not going
虽然会有模糊现象 但我们基本上
to average with a window size of 35. We need to design window sizes that are
不会用 35x35 的窗口做平均处理 对特定的问题
appropriate for the particular problem. For example, if we have this image and we
我们需要设计出合适大小的窗口 比如 在这张图上
want to get rid of some of the very small objects in the image.
我们想要去除那些非常小的物体
We, maybe they're noise or maybe they're basically stars or particles that we
可能那些是噪点 或是一些星球 亦或是一些小颗粒
don't care about them too much. Then, we can do a local filter of this
总之我们不在意 接着我们就可以对这个图像做局部滤波处理
image. In this case, it was used a 15 by 15
在这个例子中 我们使用了 15x15 大小的窗口
We're blurring the image but we're
虽然这张图片变得模糊了
somehow getting rid of these small particles.
但是我们去除了这些小颗粒
So, a small particle here will be basically average with a lot of black
这儿的一个小颗粒会被周围的深色像素平均化
pixels around it. And then, it's value will go so much
接着 它的灰度值就会变得非常小
down, so much close to zero then when I threshold I get basically only the
非常接近于0 当我对其阈值处理后
regions of interest, the larger and the very bright regions.
我基本上得到了我想要的区域 也就是更大 更明亮的区域
So, we first blur and then we threshold. And we got rid of all these which we
首先我们模糊化 然后做阈值处理 这样我们可以去除噪点
consider noise and we only get the really important objects in scene.
得到图像中对我们最重要的物体
So this very simple operation is very powerful for tasks like this.
这个简单操作对这样的任务非常有效
More interesting, this very simple averaging operation has really
更有趣的是 这个非常简单的平均处理
interesting mathematical properties that I'm going to explain next.
有着很有趣的数学特性 我会在接下来解释这一点
And those are important because they're going to help us to develop other type of
这些性质非常重要 因为它们能帮助我们开发其它类型的平均处理
averaging operations that, for example, do not blur edges.
比如 不会模糊边缘的平均处理
And we're going to do that explanation of the mathematical properties and
我们将在下一次视频中解释这些数学性质
relationships that this simple averaging has with other structures in the next
以及简单的平均操作与其它结构的关系
video. Thank you.
谢谢大家 // 果壳教育无边界字幕组 | 玉米Yummy | 某音某莹 | 小白_远游